Mighty Little Defenders 11 – New Wild Cosmos.
Final Resolution
Episode 38
That was a close call.
My wings…they seem better than before.
So, they really were treating me.
I need to get out of here fast.
You…
Quick, save that flower!
Xi Huahua!
You are the only ones who successfully gathered the trial materials this time.
Didn’t see that coming, did you?
Everyone who might have gotten in the way
was taken care of by the accidents I staged.
Now I can get the fragment without a hitch.
Wait a minute.
How is this possible? I had already…
Looks like this match is a draw.
You’ve got some skills.
Congratulations, the Flower Baby trial begins tomorrow.
Make your final preparations today.
Tomorrow?
That means there’s still a chance.
Mentor Mei Huahua,
Good.
As expected of Xi Huahua.
He managed to help Lan Baobao find a Spark—impressive.
It was really bad luck, though.
If we hadn’t run into some unexpected trouble,
our Flower Babies would have successfully obtained a Spark too.
Unexpected trouble?
You encountered that too?
In all these years, it was the first time so many things came crashing down.
Was it really just an accident?
We encountered it too.
What?
So, you experienced it as well.
As expected of Xi Huahua—he can even dodge accidents.
It’s Lan Baobao.
He didn’t just save himself; he saved me too.
Lan Baobao.
That’s certainly true.
Lan Baobao has become so outstanding, too.
We haven’t seen an outstanding flower since Nuan Huahua.
Don’t let the Elder hear that, or he’ll be heartbroken.
Nuan Huahua?
Don’t you know about Nuan Huahua?
Of course I do.
You don’t mean to tell me you don’t know?
How could I not know?
A long time ago,
the Elder carefully cultivated a flower just as outstanding as you.
That flower actually violated the Flower Tribe’s rules,
associating with the silt and eventually joining the Silt Tribe.
Smart.
Indeed.
Don’t move; this healing mud will cure you.
Th-thank you.
How did you find me?
We searched the silt flats for a long time but couldn’t find you.
Queen Nuan was worried that the bugs had taken you away.
It was she who led the Silt Tribe people to find you, risking everything.
I treated you all with such disdain, yet you still saved me.
That’s simply because you didn’t understand us.
You’re injured, too.
And…
You are a flower.
Could it be that you are the flower who, back then, defied the Flower Tribe’s rules
and joined the Silt Tribe?
Yes, I am the traitor you speak of.
Why?
Why did you defy the Flower Tribe’s rules back then
and end up joining the Silt Tribe?
It wasn’t a matter of breaking rules or not.
We all live under the same tree.
Why is the Flower Tribe considered good, while the Silt Tribe is seen as bad?
Because…
they just eat, drink, and play in the mud all day, neglecting any real work.
That’s what I thought too, until…
one day, while I was out tending to the flowers,
I accidentally fell into the Silt Area.
Arriving there for the first time,
I found the place filthy and chaotic.
I wanted to fly back up to the tree,
but discovered my wing was injured.
That’s when the Silt Tribe appeared.
The way they treated me…It was far beyond anything I had imagined.
They actually helped treat my wings.
They treated me very kindly during my stay.
They gave me withered-leaf mushroom soup to drink.
They took me for a mud bath.
I found this place fascinating.
And they certainly aren’t lazy.
Every day, they use silt to protect the roots of the Xilan Tree.
To them, the mud is just like pollen is to us—
wonderful and full of power.
But as the Flower Babies only wanted to evolve into the Flower Tribe
and not into the Silt Tribe,
the number of Silt Tribe members was dwindling year by year.
If things went on like this, the Silt Tribe would inevitably lose their last remaining habitat.
And I was worried that the Xilan Tree would be affected as a result.
So, I decided to become one of them.
I ate and drank with them,
and wielded the power of the silt alongside them.
They made me realize
that protecting the Xilan Tree should be our shared responsibility.
I was truly happy during that time.
So that’s what happened.
Later, I told the Elder about my experiences here.
We had been misunderstanding the Silt Tribe all along.
They were all born to weed and till the soil for the Xilan Tree.
Just because you met the Silt Tribe once,
you want to question the rules established by generations of Flower Tribe Elders?
Perhaps the Flower Tribe Elders were wrong from the very beginning.
Silence!
How could the former Elders possibly be wrong?
No flower has ever spoken like this before.
You are not worthy of being a flower.
I understand.
Thank you, Mentor, for all your guidance.
A bunch of stubborn, obstinate flowers—it’s infuriating.
Let’s put the past behind us.
The most important thing is
that our Xilan Tree continues to grow strong and healthy.
Was this really an accident?
I’m going out for a moment; I’ll be right back.
No, I just can’t stop worrying.
I have to go check on Lan Baobao.
I never imagined I could also evolve into a flower.
I need to prepare a grand gift to properly thank Mentor Xi Huahua.
To ensure my plan goes off without a hitch, you have to meet with an accident today.
So, you’re the culprit behind these accidents.
Who exactly are you?
You don’t need to know.
What kind of ability is this? This certainly isn’t the power of flowers.
Watch out for a group of people who might interfere with our operation.
Be especially wary of this guy; he can wield strange powers.
Could it be…I’ll settle the score with you later.
She got away.
Darn, I’m out of energy right now.
Who…exactly are you?
Where are you all going?
The bugs have been getting more and more rampant lately.
If this keeps up, they’ll devour all our food.
So, I want to go to the Bug Nest
and get our food back.
You’d better head back now.
But don’t mention that you met the Silt Tribe.
Otherwise, you’ll end up just like me.
But those bugs look really tough.
We’ll just have to bite the bullet and face them.
Planie, those bugs are dangerous.
Maybe you should stay here for now.
I want to help out, too. If I can’t even fight off these bugs,
how am I supposed to save my world?
Alright.
Just be careful and stay in the back.
Is everyone ready?
Let’s go.
Because I know…
that at our core, we are all striving for the Xilan Tree.
That bug is formidable.
We’ll just have to bite the bullet and face them.
Who…who exactly are you?
Where are the wings that represent you are a member of the Flower Tribe?
I’m sorry, I…
I am not Xi Huahua.
I knew it.
How could the most outstanding flower possibly choose me—the worst Flower Baby?
So, it was all a lie.
What effort?
What perseverance?
It was all a lie.
I—didn’t—
There’s no way I could become a flower.
No…
You liar! I hate you!
I never want to see you again!
Lan Baobao
To be continued